Benjamin Graham Oats

Mobile number

07423067306

Email address benoats@gmail.com Address 65 Belgrave Road Leigh On Sea Essex SS9 5EL

Website (currently under rebuild)

benoats.co

Personal statement

Experienced in managing staff and evaluating the strength of individuals to ensure that the team work effectively and efficiently. My passion is science and technology. I subscribe to news feeds keeping me up to date with the latest developments in technology and scientific theory.

People describe me as optimistic, I always believe things can be improved or run more efficiently. I work well in a team where I can put forward my ideas and explain the benefits whilst also listening to others and debating possible development or improvements. I welcome constructive feedback on my own ideas.

I hope to be part of the developing web community, working with the latest technology and researching better ways including up and coming techniques and methods.

Education

University of Greenwich BSc (Hons) Web Technologies 2012 to 2016 (Industry placement year)

Final Year Modules	
Dissertation	
Content Management Systems	

Information System Management Web Enterprise Systems Development

Digital Future

Grade

(Grade due summer 2016) (Grade due summer 2016)

72%

(Grade due summer 2016)

53%

56%

53%

Second Year ModulesGradeWeb Technologies82%Web Database Application77%Database Application Technologies76%Application And Web Development74%Visual Application Development71%

Application And Web Development
Visual Application Development
Professionalism In The Digital Workplace
Interactive Design

Freshers Year ModulesGradeComputing and programming72%Digital Media64%Multimedia Games Design And Development62%Visual Story Telling50%

Summer University

2011

CourseGradeInformation Technology80%

Bexley College (Access)

2010 - 2011

CourseCreditsAwarding BodyLevel 366OCN LondonLevel 26OCN London

Cecil Jones High School (GCSE)

1998 - 2002

Grade	GCSE's
В	2
C	4
D	3

Skills

Computing

- PHP MVC OOP
- HTML
- · CSS and SASS
- GRUNT
- · JavaScript and Jquery
- SQL
- · XML and JSON
- Wordpress, Joomla
- GIT

Professional

- · Critical thinking
- Marketing
- · Professional
- · Software engineering
- Agile SCRUM
- Unified modelling language (UML)
- Project Management
- · Time and deadline management
- · Project team working and presentation skills

Work experience

ClearBooks PLC May 2014 - July 2015

Position

Front End Developer / SEO Consultant

Roles:

- Develop new features application side and marketing site
- Implement designs developed with design team
- Push new ideas and think of ways to grow the system
- · Maintain and update legacy code
- · Research and develop SEO strategies
- · Monitor and report on SEO developments

Delta Force Paintball March 2013 - July 2014

Position

Senior Marshal / Head Of On-Site Sales

Roles:

- · Meet and greet new and arriving clients sign them in whilst selling optional packages and explaining what will happen through the day
- To take out a group of players up to 100 with a marshal or game runner, run a paintball match
- · Assign rolls to individual members of staff and make sure their objective is completed on time and effectively
- Effective upkeep and maintenance of the centre

Essex Digital Media 2012 (summer)

Position

Developer / Designer / SEO

Roles:

- Design logo and graphics
- Optimise all sites company wide for search engines (SEO)
- · Manage Google Adwords and Google Adsense company wide
- Set up and maintain internal network for company

Bexbase Development 2008 - 2012 (part time)

Position

Developer / Designer / SEO

Roles:

- Develop and design new systems for clients including software engineering plans
- Optimise site for ultimate speed and search engine effectiveness
- Handle new clientele write up proposals and obtain signature
- Renew hosting with client each year and site maintenance

Hobbies

• Gym

• Golf

• Paintball

Sports and fitness

- Interests
- FinanceDevelopment and design
- Computing
 - Gaming
 - Gardening
 - Sci-fi
 - Algorithms

Recreation

- Reading
- BloggingTravelling
- Restaurants
- Films
- Turning maths into code

References

Available On Request